the situation we want to consider next
is what if we need to do more than one
broadcast so let's say we have this
situation you know we have some
instructions renamed there is a register
file here we have some reservation
stations but the situation is that
somehow this divide here has finished in
the multiply divide unit at the same
cycle when the add here has finished in
the add unit and now we if we have only
one of these broadcast buses that we can
use to broadcast the result the question
is which one of these two goes first
there are first of all several
possibilities for how to support this in
harder for example you could have a
separate broadcast bus for each of the
units so normally you have one of these
buses if you have a separate bus note
that there would be twice as many
comparators basically for each of the
operands for each of the instructions in
the reservation stations we need to try
to match each of the tags that are being
broadcast and be able to select the
result or not depending on whether it
matches so there would be twice as much
matching Hardware if we had two buses
similarly here and here you would have
to be able to write two results and so
on so if we have only one bus then the
question is which one do we broadcast
and usually you either just make one
unit be the highest priority unit and
the other ones are kind of less priority
than that so that you always know I mean
you we need to choose very quickly which
one is going to be broadcast it doesn't
matter so much which one it is as much
as it matters that it's only one so
basically one of them needs to be picked
a very common heuristic is that if one
of the units is known to be slower than
the other let's say that the
multiplication and divide are slower
than adds and subtracts and so on which
is usually the case then what you want
to do is give the priority to the slower
unit why well because those instructions
have been executing for a while longer
so what's going to happen is those
instructions
are gonna have more dependencies
probably waiting for them pretty much
there are more instructions piled up to
use these results so it's so it's kind
of like an age-based thing but instead
of considering the age of each
instruction in which case we would have
to carry additionally
Meishan here what we do is we simply
give the priority to the slower unit so
this is a very common heuristic and
that's usually what ends up being used
if you really want to be kind of better
than that then you would you know carry
the edge of the instruction in which
case you can do HBase thing which
amounts to almost the same thing because
usually these instructions going to be
older here just because they're kind of
slower to execute to begin with or you
do something slightly more advanced than
that but again it's a very common
heuristic that we just used basically
the multiplication divided unit is going
to have priority in this case over the
add and subtract unit